On behalf of the Predential Assurance
Company, it is my very pleasant duty to
welcome you here
today. The face of
prudence, an iconic
image known by millions around the world
and representing our company. A company
with over 165 years of
history. Our powerful brand is wellknown
and highly regarded.
We've come a long
way, but to really understand the
present, we must first understand our
past.
1848. Industrialization is sweeping
across Europe, bringing both uncertainty
and opportunity for all classes. There's
a demand for better workers rights.
People are looking for a sense of
security. And in this year on the 30th
of May, a group of Victorian gentlemen
respond to these turbulent times by
forming the credential mutual assurance
investment and loan association. Its aim
to infix habits of prudence among many
individuals to represent the values of
the business. The figure of prudence is
adopted as the symbol of the company. To
this day, she still carries her arrow
signifying strength of purpose. Serpent,
the ancient symbol of wisdom and mirror,
representing
self-awareness. 1854, the company widens
its reach by opening its industrial
branch, introducing a new concept, penny
policies for the industrial workingclass
population. To build the business, the
company introduces a new breed of
salesmen who travel doortodoor armed
with statistics and tables. The men from
the
Prew. And with this new market, sales
grow
dramatically.
1871. The company is the first in the
city of London to employ women as
clarks. Through the 1870s, the company
grows considerably. In 1873, there are
47 agents. By 1888, there are
10,69. By 1879, the company has outgrown
its premises at Lgate Hill and moves
into the striking, purpose-built Hoben
Bar's
headquarters. By 1898, Credential has
become the number one life company in
the United Kingdom. With almost 30
million pounds in accumulated funds,
it's now at the heart of everyday life.
Nearly one in three households has a
policy with the
crew. April 14th, 1912, SS Titanic sinks
on its maiden voyage. Credential
promptly pays out claims on 292
passengers. Hardly any disaster could
occur without Credential in some way,
providing security to the deprived and
bereff.
By the end of the First World War,
Credential has paid claims representing
almost a third of the British soldiers
killed. In 1919, Credential offers
general insurance for the first time,
which enables the company to start an
extraordinary international
expansion in India. In 1923, the first
overseas life branch is established with
the first policy being sold to a tea
planter in Asam. The business soon
covered the whole of the subcontinent
with offices in Bombay, Kolkata, Salon,
and Delhi. In 1924, Credential expands
to Malaysia and by 1931, a branch is
established in Raffle Square, Singapore.
By 1939, Credential's overseas business
is rivaling the success of its UK
operations. By the end of the Second
World War, Credential has paid5 million
in claims on nearly 110,000
deaths. 1949, the famous Man from the
Prew advertising campaign is launched.
[Music]
1967 12 million people watch the first
ever credential commercials on British
television. The man from the Pue is
truly established as a household name.
Talk it over with the man from the
credential. Throughout the 70s and 80s,
Credential continues to grow and respond
to customers changing needs. In 1986,
Credential gains a firm foothold in the
United States, the world's largest life
insurance and retirement savings market.
With the acquisition of Jackson National
Life Insurance Company, with 78 million
baby boomers reaching retirement over
the next 20 years, Jackson is well
placed to help them meet their needs for
retirement
income. 1994 is a milestone year as
Credential recognizing the high
potential for growth and expansion
across Asia establishes Credential
Corporation Asia. The regional head
office in Hong Kong sets out to expand
operations beyond Malaysia, Singapore,
and Hong Kong. Businesses are soon
established in Indonesia, Thailand,
Vietnam, and the Philippines. In the UK,
in 1999, Credential strengthens the
group's investment management
opportunities with the acquisition of
fund managers MNG. M&G itself has a long
history of innovation. In 1931, the
company launched the first ever unit
trust in the United
Kingdom. Over the next 12 years,
Credential is to become the leading
international life insurer in Asia,
expanding into 13 markets and meeting
the savings and protection needs of a
fast growing middle class across the
region. Credential has established
strong distribution channels including
partnerships with banks across the
region and an extensive network of
trained
agents. 2012 Credentials Asia Asset
Management Business, one of the leading
fund managers in the region is rebranded
as East Spring Investments, paving the
way for its expansion into the US in the
same
year. In the United Kingdom, Credential
is a leading life and pensions provider
to around 7 million customers with a
focus on pensions saving and
investments.
Credential now has around 24 million
insurance customers, over 26,000
employees, more than400,000 agents in
Asia, four stock exchange listings in
London, Hong Kong, New York, and
Singapore, and more than400 billion
pounds of assets under management. We've
come a long way, not only with the
expansion of our business, but also our
work in giving back to the communities
we live and work in. Today, Credential
is a company with a broader scope, a
wider geographic spread, and greater
investment power than could ever have
been imagined in 1848. But our founding
principles of integrity, security, and
prudence still guide us in promoting
long-term financial security for our
customers and building social and
economic value in our communities around
the world.
[Music]